{
	"nutrition": [
		{
			"id": "d4ac56cf-1403-4c75-af54-d58d5b914782",
			"question": "What is an apple?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "A fruit,",
			"options": [
				"A fruit",
				"an orange"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "1437dd15-4d2f-4b1a-bd44-182f497e3397",
			"question": "What is the likely outcome of a person consuming more energy than they expend over an extended period of time?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Weight gain",
			"options": [
				"Steady weight",
				"Weight loss",
				"Weight gain",
				"Muscle gain"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "dbf0897b-0f57-441c-b33c-d961d1482193",
			"question": "What unit is energy consumption measured in?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Calories",
			"options": [
				"Calories",
				"Watts",
				"Kilograms",
				"Newtons"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "18ae8d4e-c33e-4098-b321-d6b1b0bd7c38",
			"question": "Which of these macronutrients is used to rebuild the muscle tissues that are damaged by heavy training?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Proteins,",
			"options": [
				"Carbohydrates",
				"Fats",
				"Proteins",
				"Fruits"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "c6694fa3-e87d-4696-90b6-dd5776dacbb3",
			"question": "Which of these sources of energy can be considered to be a simple carbohydrate?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Fructose (from fruit)",
			"options": [
				"Potato",
				"Rice",
				"Fructose (from fruit)",
				"Chicken"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "554e1ba8-9959-4e37-aea1-664149136819",
			"question": "Which of these forms of fat is an essential feature of a balanced diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Polyunsaturated fats",
			"options": [
				"Saturated fats",
				"Polyunsaturated fats",
				"Trans fats",
				"Electrolyte fat"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "cae6ac2b-6cb4-4f39-8f48-1df537556cb5",
			"question": "Which mineral, found in fish and broccoli, is essential for bone growth and strength?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Calcium",
			"options": [
				"Potassium",
				"Zinc",
				"Calcium",
				"Magnesium"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "93fd54d8-15d3-4b41-9320-4f14b4cc0262",
			"question": "Which condition is likely to occur if a marathon runner competes in hot conditions without consuming enough water?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Dehydration",
			"options": [
				"Hydration",
				"Dehydration",
				"Hypertension",
				"Shin splints"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "40d9adc0-6d20-42e6-b3ac-e68c81f44dcb",
			"question": "What is the role of insoluble fibre in the human body?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "To keep the bowels healthy",
			"options": [
				"To reduce cholesterol",
				"To rehydrate",
				"To keep the bowels healthy",
				"To increase blood sugar levels"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "7afc56af-cc15-4511-863f-56b9abd01b2b",
			"question": "According to the eatwell plate, what is the key to a healthy diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Fruit and vegetables",
			"options": [
				"Variety",
				"Fruit and vegetables",
				"Proteins",
				"Chia seeds"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "25110194-953f-4fde-ba11-2cdfae6ac7b4",
			"question": "In what form are complex carbohydrates stored in the human body?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"answer": "Glucose",
			"options": [
				"Glucose",
				"Fats",
				"Glycogen",
				"Muscle"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "731e79ec-2584-4126-8bf4-070d877804c4",
			"question": "Why are proteins important in a balanced diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "They are needed for growth and repair",
			"options": [
				"They provide vital minerals",
				"They are a high-energy source",
				"They are needed for growth and repair",
				"The increase speed of digestion"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "64ad9a63-5ee5-4188-bc44-7b7bd2c2312e",
			"question": "Which component do cheese, butter and margarine have in common?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "Lipids",
			"options": [
				"Lipids",
				"Carbohydrates",
				"Proteins",
				"Onion"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "f663df78-5708-47ee-bfe5-3931f0292b72",
			"question": "What can happen to someone with too little vitamin A in their diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "They get night blindness",
			"options": [
				"They get beriberi",
				"They get scurvy",
				"They get night blindness",
				"Sleeplessness"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "fb1a1d01-0dd2-42cd-bc4f-4fdce4c4dc79",
			"question": "What can happen to someone with too little vitamin C in their diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "They get scurvy",
			"options": [
				"They get scurvy",
				"They get night blindness",
				"They get anaemia",
				"Sleeplessness"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "03b07481-d763-4636-875c-4fc98d63b66c",
			"question": "What can happen to someone with too little vitamin D in their diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "They get rickets",
			"options": [
				"Their blood does not clot properly",
				"They get rickets",
				"They get scurvy",
				"They get night blindness"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "66d6d5ad-acf9-4505-881c-b0774669e23c",
			"question": "Which of these is a typical symptom of too little iron in the diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "Anaemia",
			"options": [
				"Anaemia",
				"Leukaemia",
				"Uraemia",
				"Dementia"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "69cef021-07c4-43b8-87d3-03f37ade2f03",
			"question": "Why is fibre important in the diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "It helps to prevent constipation",
			"options": [
				"It can be digested to form simple sugars, needed for energy",
				"It helps to prevent constipation",
				"It is a good source of vitamin C",
				"Reduces glycogen levels"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "68c21837-9ca5-41e0-8a15-8738b486c52b",
			"question": "What is a 'balanced' diet?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "A diet with the different components present in appropriate proportions",
			"options": [
				"A diet with little fat and salt in it",
				"A diet with the different components present in appropriate proportions",
				"A diet with equal amounts of lipids, proteins and carbohydrates in it",
				"A diet with no sugar"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "096e28ec-ceb0-4d54-80ef-414aec05c862",
			"question": "Who is likely to need the most energy in their daily food intake?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "A 16 year old teenager",
			"options": [
				"A newborn baby",
				"A 6 year old child",
				"A 16 year old teenager",
				"A 12 year old"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "da9ff2bc-7b06-4a80-b5c0-35d4cc008243",
			"question": "For each question you should shade in one box. An example is shown below. Which food is high in protein?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "Cheese",
			"options": [
				"Cabbage",
				"Cheese",
				"Oranges",
				"Cucumber"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "d94522ed-a736-4ac2-bcbb-4278a5767dac",
			"question": "Which one of the toppings is highest in dietary fibre? A Cheddar cheese?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "Grilled tomatoes ",
			"options": [
				"Cheddar cheese",
				"Orange marmalade",
				"Baked beans ",
				"Grilled tomatoes "
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "dbfcf7a1-7e60-4f65-a174-469fd5d1f765",
			"question": "Which one of the toppings is highest in dietary fibre? A Cheddar cheese?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "Cheddar cheese ",
			"options": [
				"Cheddar cheese",
				"Orange marmalade",
				"Baked beans",
				"Grilled tomatoes"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "568d2f12-73b0-47d7-a2e5-b0d1ca47dde4",
			"question": "What is a calorie?",
			"type": "text",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"answer": "The calorie is a unit of energy defined as the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of a quantity of water by one degree",
			"options": [
				"The calorie is a unit of energy defined as the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of a quantity of water by one degree"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "09d5de76-4843-45b8-a39d-08a1b92b4552",
			"question": "There is a small amount of ____ herding that occurs in both Lobitos and Piedritas?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Goat",
			"options": [
				" Goat, Sheep, Cow, Llamas "
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "4cc8b407-35f7-4bb9-81c5-9967d363198f",
			"question": " What is an essential component of the local economy of Lobitos?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Artisinal fishing",
			"options": [
				" Artisinal fishing , tour guides, mining, coffee bean production "
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "bc611d12-884a-4995-912e-84cb4e1cc2cd",
			"question": "What does Ecoswell believe that improvements in the practice of ____ that could have benefits for regenerating the dry forest as ecotourism?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Goat herding",
			"options": [
				" Goat herding , Surfing, Restaurants, Transport "
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "77da7b08-d5b9-4e59-a714-430587ceb665",
			"question": "What place in Talara sells food supplies near the central market?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "La Parada (The Stop)",
			"options": [
				" La Parada (The Stop), La Costa, La Plaza, La Donda"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "fb060ed2-c2d1-420f-ba35-8a7e3749ec95",
			"question": "The local groundwater in Lobitos is salty and viewed as unsuitable for ___?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Farming",
			"options": [
				" Farming , Fishing, Cooking, Drinking"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "97e698f7-174d-4d94-8148-7d879849b634",
			"question": "In Lobitos, who owns and oversees the pier, which is essential to the fishing industry?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "The regional government",
			"options": [
				" The regional government , Privately owned, Piedritas officials, American officials"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "151216a3-8b04-4968-b7cd-92aaa653d703",
			"question": "What, is Juan the Vice President of the Lobitos Artisanal Fisherman’s Guild Association trying to improve?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "The gear and equipment fishermen use",
			"options": [
				" The gear and equipment fishermen use , Surfing at the beach,  Hotels, Restaurants "
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "07a8f405-3a54-446c-a23d-b106e2165549",
			"question": "Some reefs in Lobitos are inaccessible to fishers due to their proximity to  ____?",
			"type": "text",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Oil Platforms",
			"options": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "191939f5-4042-43df-a13a-068bfc4efd22",
			"question": "What are the two main types of fishing in Lobitos and Piedritas?",
			"type": "text",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Nylon fishing and net fishing",
			"options": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "294d417d-cf05-4d91-a3a2-34c65ba95834",
			"question": "What do the goat farmers produce, which they sell locally?",
			"type": "text",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Goat milk and cheese",
			"options": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "1963944a-0ce9-44f1-87e8-35246efce5e4",
			"question": "Which mineral is needed to maintain healthy bones and teeth?",
			"type": "multiple-choice",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Calcium",
			"options": [
				"Vitamin D",
				"Iron",
				"Calcium",
				"Magnesium"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "a8515598-fca2-4a39-9b96-3c62fb771a40",
			"question": "What is an issue that the tourist complain about regarding the fish caught in Lobitos?",
			"type": "text ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Darker flesh and has some spines",
			"options": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"id": "7108638e-7f83-4903-9aef-b8a86a813853",
			"question": "Why do the fishers from Lobitos not sell their fish directly to the locals?",
			"type": " multiple-choice ",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"answer": "Enforced punishments",
			"options": [
				" Enforced punishments, Lack of knowledge, Time management, Language Barrier"
			]
		}
	]
}